<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on lyao&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/en/post/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on lyao&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>谷栗杳</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>O&#39; Henrry&#39;s short story reading notes</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/en/p/o-henrrys-short-story-reading-notes/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/en/p/o-henrrys-short-story-reading-notes/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-gift-of-the-magi&#34;&gt;The Gift of the Magi
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This story focuses on Jim and Della, a loving but impoverished couple in an apartment, who both sell their most valuable things in order to buy each other their most beloved gifts - Jim sells his prized pocket watch, and Della sells her long, proud hair. Yet the gifts they buy for each other require exactly these things as a foundation - Della buys a long chain for Jim&amp;rsquo;s pocket watch for decoration, and Jim buys a comb for Della&amp;rsquo;s hair. One is struck by the unexpectedness of the situation, but also by their true love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-last-leaf&#34;&gt;The Last Leaf
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This story is mainly about a girl with Pneumonia, Johnsy, because the leaves of the vines outside of window are about to fall off, touched the feelings, and lost the confidentce in life, but did not expect that even after a night of wind and rain, the last leaf is still not blown off, thus regained the courage to live, after getting well, and found that the original leaf is downstairs, the painter who is also suffering from Pneumonia, Mr. Behrman, in order to encourage Johnsy to paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-twenty-years&#34;&gt;After Twenty Years
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This story is mainly about two old friends who agree to meet after 20 years. One of them become police officer, but realizes that his old friend has become a wanted man in Mexico, and cannot bear to arrest him, so he asks his other plainclothes colleague to do it for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cop-and-the-anthem&#34;&gt;The Cop and the Anthem
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The story is mainly about Soapy, a social marginalized man, who tries a various ways to commit crime intending to be caught and imprisoned, hoping to get through the cold winter, all of which end in failure. Just as he was sitting on a park bench, disheartened, he heard a beautiful song coming from the church, envoking the goodness of his heart. However, as he was planning to get a proper job and change his life with his own hands, he was arrested for loitering and sentenced to three month in prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-service-of-love&#34;&gt;A Service of Love
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The story is about a poor couple, Joe and Delia, who came to New York City to pursue their dream of making art, but are unable to beat the reality of making a living through art. On the one hand, they don&amp;rsquo;t want their other half to give up their dream easily, on the other hand, they have to keep to live, so they hide the truth from each other, pretending they are still doing art-related work on the one hand, and doing other jobs to make a living on the other, until Delia gets sick one time before revealing the truth to each other, which makes people sigh for their love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;while-the-auto-waits&#34;&gt;While the Auto Waits
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article is mainly about a man stumbles upon a women sitting on a bench while wandering in a park. The woman claims to be an aristocrat who wants to experience life as a commoner, and that luxury automobile parked around the corner of the park is hers. The man claimed to be a cashier at a restaurant. Their true identities are reversed: the woman is a restaurant cashier, the the man is an aristocrat, and the car is belong to him, which is very ironic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;07-the-romance-of-a-busy-broker&#34;&gt;07 The Romance of a Busy Broker
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The article focuses on Maxwell, a stockbroker who has a very busy schedule, but takes time out of his busy schedule to propose to his stenographer subordinate, Leslie, only to find out that they were married at 8:00 p.m. last night in a church. The article explores the possible consequences of being too obsessed with work - neglecting or forgetting important aspects of life such as family and relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;08-furnished-room-for-rent&#34;&gt;08 Furnished Room for Rent
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This story is about a man who travels from city to city in search of his missing beloved. At a hotel, he realizes through some clues that his current room may have been occupied by his beloved, so he goes to ask the landlord about it, but to no avail. Feeling that hope is lost and that he has lost his motivation for life, he take his life in the room. The next day, the landlords got together to discuss that a girl in the man&amp;rsquo;s room had also committed suicide a while ago. This essay discusses the main idea that people are prone to mental breakdown when they are lonely and helpless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;09-confessions-of--a-humorist&#34;&gt;09 Confessions of  a Humorist
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article follows a man as a former humorist through his journey from discovering a talent for humor, to becoming a professional humorist, and then out of humorist status. After becoming a humorist, the man had to think of funny things every minute of every day, take material from other people, and stop doing it for the sake of making people laugh, which caused him to have poor relationships with those around him as well as those in his family. After a certain conversation with a man in a solemn profession, he came to his senses and went back to his old style of acting and writing and became naturally light-hearted again, and as a result, improved his relationship with his neighbors and family. This article reveals the price that can be paid for what the public sees as humor, and shows the pain that comes when a hobby becomes a profession.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
